<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Protocols</title>
    <link>https://social-protocols.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Social Protocols</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://social-protocols.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deliberative Consensus Protocols</title>
      <link>https://social-protocols.org/deliberative-consensus-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://social-protocols.org/deliberative-consensus-protocols/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: Scalable Group Decision-Making A deliberative consensus protocol is a process that online groups can use to make decisions. It&amp;rsquo;s designed to produce good decisions that are fair and manifest the collective intelligence of the group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://social-protocols.org/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://social-protocols.org/resources/</guid>
      <description>This is a curated list of resources we found helpful along the way. Links to commercial websites are not affiliate links. If you spot any errors (e.g., if we have done a poor job summarizing your article or project), feel free to raise an issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Building Jabble: Social Media from the Future</title>
      <link>https://social-protocols.org/social-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://social-protocols.org/social-network/</guid>
      <description>We are in the process of creating a social media platform based on what we&amp;rsquo;ve learned from our experiments during the past years. The core of our concepts is a suite of novel algorithms that distribute attention over content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Alignment Technology</title>
      <link>https://social-protocols.org/human-alignment-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://social-protocols.org/human-alignment-technology/</guid>
      <description>Human alignment, the process of establishing shared understanding among individuals, is crucial for effective collaboration and organization. It is essential for civilizations to flourish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Social Protocols</title>
      <link>https://social-protocols.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://social-protocols.org/about/</guid>
      <description>The goal of Social Protocols is to enhance collective intelligence. We are working on open algorithms and protocols that benefit large scale human interaction.
Check out our Projects.
Follow us on Mastodon or Twitter, or send a mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://social-protocols.org/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://social-protocols.org/projects/</guid>
      <description>Jabble (2023) We are in the process of creating a social media platform based on what we&amp;rsquo;ve learned from our experiments during the past years: (Jabble) based on our Global Brain Algorithm, which converts a social media platform into a distributed brain, resulting in a whole that is more intelligent than the individual human parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Deserves Our Attention?</title>
      <link>https://social-protocols.org/what-deserves-our-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://social-protocols.org/what-deserves-our-attention/</guid>
      <description>Every online community has rules that determine how the attention of the community is directed. For example in an online forum, the most up-voted posts may be shown on at the top of the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Law of Attention</title>
      <link>https://social-protocols.org/the-law-of-attention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://social-protocols.org/the-law-of-attention/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I argue that we can apply game theory to explain and control the behaviors that dominate in an online community. Not only can game theory explain why misinformation and abuse are so common in social platforms, it can be used to design social platforms that will be filled with honest, informed, civil, and behavior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truthtelling Games</title>
      <link>https://social-protocols.org/truthtelling-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://social-protocols.org/truthtelling-games/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I will use game theory to explain why, under certain conditions, otherwise dishonest Internet people will behave with scrupulous honesty, and how social platforms can be intentionally engineered to create these conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give Truth the Advantage</title>
      <link>https://social-protocols.org/give-truth-the-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://social-protocols.org/give-truth-the-advantage/</guid>
      <description>Everyone knows that the infamous social media algorithms promote the spread of false and misleading information on the Internet. But could they be engineered to do the opposite?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Deliberative Poll</title>
      <link>https://social-protocols.org/the-deliberative-poll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 13:40:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://social-protocols.org/the-deliberative-poll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A deliberative poll measures the &lt;strong&gt;informed opinion&lt;/strong&gt; of a group of people who have participated in a discussion about the topic of the poll. This essay introduces a method for integrating deliberative polling into online discussions in social platforms, in order to discover the informed opinion of a group.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
