<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles on Social Protocols</title><link>https://example.org/articles/</link><description>Recent content in Articles on Social Protocols</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 18:26:46 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.org/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deliberative Consensus Protocols</title><link>https://example.org/deliberative-consensus-protocols/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/deliberative-consensus-protocols/</guid><description>Introduction: Scalable Group Decision-Making A deliberative consensus protocol is a process that online groups can use to make decisions. It&amp;rsquo;s designed to produce good decisions that are fair and manifest the collective intelligence of the group.</description></item><item><title>What Is a Social Protocol?</title><link>https://example.org/what-is-a-social-protocol/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/what-is-a-social-protocol/</guid><description>Introduction The rules that determine what gets attention in social platforms are often referred to as &amp;ldquo;algorithms&amp;rdquo;. But algorithms are only part of the story. Another way of understanding social platforms is as social protocols that a community uses to decide where to allocate its collective attention.</description></item><item><title>Human Alignment Technology</title><link>https://example.org/human-alignment-technology/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/human-alignment-technology/</guid><description>Human alignment, the process of establishing shared understanding among individuals, is crucial for effective collaboration and organization. It is essential for civilizations to flourish.</description></item><item><title>What Deserves Our Attention?</title><link>https://example.org/what-deserves-our-attention/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/what-deserves-our-attention/</guid><description>Every online community has rules that determine how the attention of the community is directed. For example in an online forum, the most up-voted posts may be shown on at the top of the page.</description></item><item><title>The Law of Attention</title><link>https://example.org/the-law-of-attention/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/the-law-of-attention/</guid><description>In this article, I argue that we can apply game theory to explain and control the behaviors that dominate in an online community. Not only can game theory explain why misinformation and abuse are so common in social platforms, it can be used to design social platforms that will be filled with honest, informed, civil, and behavior.</description></item><item><title>Truthtelling Games</title><link>https://example.org/truthtelling-games/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/truthtelling-games/</guid><description>In this article, I will use game theory to explain why, under certain conditions, otherwise dishonest Internet people will behave with scrupulous honesty, and how social platforms can be intentionally engineered to create these conditions.</description></item><item><title>Give Truth the Advantage</title><link>https://example.org/give-truth-the-advantage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/give-truth-the-advantage/</guid><description>Everyone knows that the infamous social media algorithms promote the spread of false and misleading information on the Internet. But could they be engineered to do the opposite?</description></item><item><title>The Deliberative Poll</title><link>https://example.org/the-deliberative-poll/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 13:40:43 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/the-deliberative-poll/</guid><description>&lt;p>A deliberative poll measures the &lt;strong>informed opinion&lt;/strong> of a group of people who have participated in a discussion about the topic of the poll. This essay introduces a method for integrating deliberative polling into online discussions in social platforms, in order to discover the informed opinion of a group.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>